A Guide to the J. Rives Childs Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
J. Rives Childs Papers 1823-1950
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9256-f
This collection consists of ca. 310 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was gifted by Mr. Childs on 1974 March 4.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Childs Papers consists primarily of memoranda, dispatches and resumes of telegrams from J. Rives Childs' consular activities, ca. 1940, in the Near East and North Africa, mainly Tangiers. Of special interest are the minutes of the Franco-American negotiations of 1939 concerning French Morocco. Also included are signed one page letters by Presidents Wilson and Truman, and a Dec. 16, 1823 signed note by President Jefferson recommending Mr. Philips as an accomplished bricklayer.
Arrangement
The collection is filed both by subject matter and chronologically.
Contents List
- Thomas Jefferson's recommendation of Mr. Phillips as a bricklayer 1823 Dec 16, ANS
- Woodrow Wilson to J. Rives Childs 1921 Mar 3, TLS
- Letter of thanks to Childs from staff in Russia 1922 Dec 20
- Memoranda re consular activities, 250 l. 1938-1940, 10 TMs (carbon)
- Minutes of Franco-American Negotiations, index, 250 l. 1939 Jun 13 - Jul 11, TMs (carbon)
- Memoranda re Near East consular activities 1940, 43 TMs (carbon)
- Miscellaneous re consular activities ca. 1940, 7 TMs (carbon)
- "The Role of Egypt in the War" 1940 Sep 26, TMs
  (2 folders)
- Dispatches to Secretary of State from Childs in Tangier, index, 300 l. 1941-1942, 117 TMs (carbon)
- Resumes of telegrams from Tangier preceding and during North African landings, and the telegrams received from the War Department, 73 l. 1941-1943, TMs
- Dispatches to Secretary of State from Childs in Tangier, 300 l. 1942-1943, 125 TMs (carbon)
- Harry S Truman to J. Rives Childs 1950 Aug 28, TLS